Good morning, Leonard.
早上好啊 Leonard
Yeah. we're gonna have to stop by
Pottery Barn on the way to work.
今天上班路上我们顺便去下陶器坊吧
(PotteryBarn 美国时尚家居购物中心)
I bought these Star Wars sheets, but
they turned out to be much too stimulating
我买了些星战床单 但实在是望而生畏
to be compatible with
a good night's sleep.
晚上老是睡不好
I don't like the way
Darth Vader stares at me.
我讨厌达斯・维达那样瞪着我
I'm not going to work.
我今天不上班
Oh, just because your career's
been stagnant for a few years,
噢 你的事业不过是停滞了几年时光
that's no reason to give up.
没理由现在就放弃啊
Sheldon, I was up all night
using the new free-electron laser
Sheldon 我整晚都在用新自由电子激光仪
for my X-ray diffraction experiment.
做我的X光衍射实验
Did the laser accidentally
burn out your retinas?
你不小心被激光灼伤了视网膜?
- No.
- Then you can drive. Let's go.
- 没有
- 那你还是能开车的 走吧
Didn't I tell you I'd be working nights and
that you'd have to make other arrangements?
我不是已经说了我整晚都在工作
你得自己另行安排嘛
- You did.
- And?
- 说了呀
- 那还要怎样?
I didn't.
可我不
Let's go.
快走吧
Good night, Sheldon.
晚安 Sheldon
But how am I going to get to work?
那我要怎么去上班呢?
- Take the bus.
- I can't take the bus anymore.
- 坐公车咯
- 我可不能再去坐公车了
They don't have seat belts, and they won't let
you latch yourself to the seat with bungee cords.
都没有安全带的说 还不让你用
蹦极绳把自己拴在椅子上
You tried to latch yourself
to the seat with bungee cords?
你试过把自己栓椅子上?
I didn't try. I succeeded.
试算啥 我都成功了呢
But for some reason, it alarmed the other
passengers and I was asked to de-bus.
可不知咋的 吓着其他乘客了
然后我就被赶下车了
Oh, you're a big boy.
You'll figure it out.
你这么大人了 会有办法的
Don't talk to me like I'm a child.
别总拿我当小孩嘛
Now, take me to return
my Star Wars sheets!
带我去退了那些星战床单啦
Penny? Penny? Penny?
Sheldon. What is it?
Sheldon 什么事?
Leonard's asleep.
Leonard睡着了
- Thanks for the update.
- No. Wait.
- 谢谢你的及时报告
- 不 等等
You have to drive me to work.
你得开车送我去上班
Yeah, I really don't think I do.
我没这义务吧
But I don't drive, and
I can't take the bus.
可我不会开车 又不能坐公车
Honey, you'll be fine as long as you
don't do that bungee cord thing, okay?
亲爱的 只要你不干绑蹦极带的傻事
你不会有事的 明白吗?
Penny.
Penny
Didn't you recently state
that you and I are friends?
前阵子你不是说我们是朋友么?
Yes, Sheldon. We are friends.
是啊 Sheldon 我们是朋友
Then I hereby invoke what I'm given to understand is
an integral part of the implied covenant of friendship.
那我就据此援引下我所理解的
作为友谊誓约必不可少的部分
The favor.
帮助
Oh, dear God.
噢 亲爱的上帝啊
I'm sorry, I didn't realize I was
interrupting your morning prayers.
真抱歉 打断你做晨间祷告了
When you're done, we'll go.
等你完了我们就走
荣誉出品
翻译: 饭特稀 多边形 王泳东
校对: penny
时间轴: 咔肉肉
Thank you for driving me to work.
多谢你开车送我
You know this is my day off, Sheldon.
Sheldon 今天我可是歇班的
Oh, good. I'm not
keeping you from anything.
噢 那好哇 我没耽误你什么事
Your "check engine" light is on.
"检查引擎"的灯亮着呢
Typically that's an indicator
to, you know, check your engine.
基本上 它的意思是要让你 检查引擎
It's fine. It's been
on for, like, a month.
没事的 都已经亮了有一个月了
Well, actually, that would
be all the more reason to...
好吧 那这么说来 你就更得去...
you know, check your engine.
检查一下引擎了
Sheldon, it's fine.
Sheldon 没事的
If it were fine, the
light wouldn't be on.
要真没事的话 灯干嘛还亮着
That's why the manufacturer installed
that light, to let you know it's not fine.
生产商装这个指示灯的目的
不就是在出问题的时候提醒你嘛
Maybe the light's broken.
大概是灯坏了吧
Is there a "check the
'check engine light' light"?
有没有"检查'检查引擎灯'指示灯"?
What?
啥?
Studies have shown that
performing tasks such as eating,
有研究表明 在开车的时候
talking on a cell phone or drinking coffee
while driving reduces one's reaction time
吃东西 打手机 或者喝咖啡等等
都会对降低人的反应敏捷度
by the same factor as
an ounce of alcohol.
就和喝了一盎司酒一样
Do you have any alcohol?
你喝酒了吗?
- Of course not.
- Too bad.
- 当然没有
- 太糟了
You're going up Euclid Avenue?
你要从Euclid大道走?
Leonard takes Los Robles Avenue.
Leonard通常走Los Robles大道
Well, good for Leonard.
Leonard真行啊
Euclid Avenue is shorter as the
crow flies, but it has speed bumps,
Euclid大道直线距离是短点
可路上有减速带啊
which appreciably increase point-to-point
drive time, making it the less efficient choice.
点对点的行车时间就显著增加
这样一来就不算高效了
But you have the conn.
不过方向盘在你手里
Of course, if you're not going
to slow down fothe speed bumps,
当然 如果你通过减速带时不减速
I withdraw my previous objection.
我收回我之前的话
Here's a fun question.
问你个有意思的问题
Do you know what the most
common street name is?
你知道最常见的街名是啥吗?
- No.
- The answer's tricky.
- 不知道
- 答案很狡猾噢
It's Second Street.
是第二大街
You see, you'd think it would be
First Street, but in most towns,
大多数人都会认为是第一大街
但在大多数城里
First Street eventually gets
renamed to something else.
第一大街最终都会被重新命名
You know, like Main
Street, Broad Street.
比方说美茵街 布罗德街
Michigan Avenue.
密歇根大道
See, Leonard and I often use our commute time to
exercise our minds with brain-teasers like that.
看没 我和Leonard总用路上时间
玩玩脑筋急转弯锻炼脑子
We also play games.
我们还做游戏
- Would you like to play one?
- No.
- 来玩个不?
- 不用了
Oh, come on. It's fun.
噢 来吧 可有意思呢
Another bump.
又不减速 弹咯
Okay. I'll say an element,
and, and you say an element
好咧 我来说一个元素名
然后 你再说一个
whose name starts with the last
letter of the one I said, okay?
像接龙一样 首尾字母相接 怎么样?
I'll start.
我先开始
Helium.
氦(helium)
Now, you could say "mercury."
你可以接"汞"(mercury)
That would give me a "y." Very
clever. That's a tough one.
我就要用"y"开头 真聪明 这有点难度
So I go with "ytterbium,"
which gets you back to "m."
那我就接"镱"(ytterbium) 你又得用"m"开头了
So you go "molybdenum,"
and I say "magnesium."
那你就接"钼"(molybdenum)
然后我接"镁"(magnesium)
You say "manganese."
你接"锰"(manganese)
I say "europium," and, then, you're
left with "mendelevium," and...
我接"铕"(europium) 然后你
就只能接"钔"(Mendelevium) 这样一来...
there are no more m's because I believe that
meitnerium should still be called ekairidium.
就没有以"m"开头的了
因为我觉得"钔"还是该叫"类铅"(Ekairidium)
So, congratulations. You win.
恭喜啊 你赢了
Do you wanna go again?
你想再来一遍吗?
Why don't we just have
a little quiet time now?
你就不能消停一会儿吗
All right.
好吧
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm finding your reckless nonchalance regarding
the check-engine light to be very troubling.
你对"检查引擎"无所谓的冷漠态度
让我感到极度不安
Get out.
下车
Well, I have to tell you that
好吧 我跟你实话实说
while I do have a theoretical understanding of
the workings of an internal combustion engine,
我的确对内燃引擎的工作原理有所了解
I'm not sure I'm capable
of performing diagnostics.
可我不确定我是否能进行故障排查
I said, "Get out."
我说"下车"
Okay. I'll give it a shot.
好吧 我来试试好了
Oh, Leonard. There you are.
噢 Leonard 你在这儿啊
I'm ready to go home.
我准备回家了
- I just got here.
- Good. Perfect timing.
- 我才刚来
- 太好了 时间算得够准的
Sheldon, I told you, I only have access
to the free-electron laser at night.
Sheldon 我跟你说过了
我只有晚上才能用自由电子激光仪
I can't drive you for
the next few weeks.
接下来几个礼拜我都不能开车送你了
No, you said you
couldn't drive me to work.
不 你只是说你不能开车送我上班
This is from work.
现在是下班
Howard, help me out here.
Howard 救救我吧
No, just for the fun of
it, I'm gonna take his side.
才不呢 为了乐子 我也要站在他那边
Now, how do you propose I get home?
那你觉得我该怎么回家?
How did you get here in the first place?
你是怎么来的?
Penny.
Penny送我来的
But I sense that's no longer an option.
但我感觉再也不可能了
Look, I need to get to the laser lab.
听着 我现在要去激光实验室
You're just gonna have to find
someone else to take you home.
你就找别人送你回去吧
Ah, damn, I picked the wrong side.
噢 可恶 我站错边了
Oh, God, not Euclid Avenue!
噢 天呐 表又走Euclid大道嘛!
Why did Howard leave you in
the middle of the road anyway?
Howard为啥在半路上把你抛下?
We had a difference of opinion.
我们意见不合
Over what?
什么事?
Whether or not he was trying to kill me.
就他是否打算杀了我这件事
For the record, I maintain he was.
提一句哈 我仍认为他要杀我
Where are you going?
你这是要上哪儿?
I'm taking you home.
送你回家啊
Oh, but I'm not going
home. It's Wednesday.
噢 可我不要回家 今天是礼拜三
Wednesday's new comic book day.
礼拜三是"漫画书淘宝"日
We have to go to the comic book store.
我们得去漫画书屋
And then, we have to stop at Soup
Plantation; it's creamy tomato soup day.
之后还得去靓汤园 今天有奶油土豆汤
And Radio Shack. There's a
sale on triple-A batteries.
还有RadioShack电子商店
三A电池在打折呢
Plus, we have to go to Pottery
Barn and return my Star Wars sheets.
此外 我们还要去一下陶器坊
我要把星战被单给退了
I have a better idea.
我有个更好的主意
You want to go to Pottery Barn first?
你打算先去陶器坊?
Can you drive me to Pottery Barn?
你能送我去陶器坊吗?
Maybe if I turn off the
night-light, I can keep the sheets.
也许我把小夜灯关了 就不用退床单了
Good morning.
早上好
Sheldon, sit down.
Sheldon 坐下
She's in my spot.
她占了我的地方
Don't look at me like that.
Everybody knows that's my spot.
别瞪我 谁都知道那是我的地方
Sheldon, you know
that we care about you.
Sheldon 你知道我们都很关心你
And it's because we care about you
that we've decided we have to speak up.
正因为如此 我们决定打开天窗说亮话
You're hurting the people
around you, sweetie.
亲爱的 你伤了我们的感情
So we made you an appointment,
and we want you to keep it.
我们给你预约了 这个你收好
Department of Motor
Vehicles New Driver Handbook?
汽车管理局新手指南
But I don't have a problem.
但我没啥要指南的啊
Sheldon, you need to learn how to drive.
Sheldon 你要学会开车
This madness has to stop.
我们不能再陪你疯了
Penny's taking you to
the DMV. I'm going to bed.
Penny会带你去车管局 我去睡觉
Why Penny?
为什么是Penny?
Because rock breaks
scissors. Good night.
因为石头赢了剪刀 晚安
All right, come on, Sheldon.
行了 走吧 Sheldon
Hold on. I have one condition.
等等 我有个条件
What?
啥啊?
We have to stop at Pottery Barn.
我们要在陶器坊那停一停
Okay.
行
And Radio Shack.
还有Radio Shack零售店
Fine.
好吧
- And the comic book store.
- All right!
- 漫画书店
- 知道了
Ooh, I want to go to
the comic book store.
我也要去漫画书店
I like comic books.
我喜欢漫画书
I just don't see why I
need a driver's license.
搞不懂我考驾照干啥
Albert Einstein never
had a driver's license.
爱因斯坦都没考过的说
Yeah, but Albert Einstein didn't make
me wet myself at 40 miles an hour.
是啊 但爱因斯坦没让我在
40英里时速下尿裤子
Yeah, and I never wanted to
kick Albert Einstein in the nuts.
我从没想过踢爱因斯坦老二
You know, I gotta ask, why didn't you just
get a license at 16 like everybody else?
我想问问 你干嘛不像其他人一样
16岁时就考到驾照呢?
I was otherwise engaged.
我在忙其他事情
Doing what?
忙什么?
Examining perturbative amplitudes
in N=4 supersymmetric theories
检测N=4超对称理论的扰动振幅
leading to a re-examination of the ultraviolet
properties of multi-loop N=8 supergravity
从而开展了利用现代扭量理论
对多线圈N=8超引力
using modern twistor theory.
紫外线特质的复查
Well, how 'bout when you were 17?
那你17岁的时候呢?
Take this to the testing
area, put your name at the top,
拿着去测试区 表格顶端写好名字
sign the bottom, answer the
questions, bring it back. Next.
在最底下签名 答完问题拿回来 下一个
Application?
你的申请表呢?
I'm actually more of a theorist.
事实上我不仅仅是一个理论家
The application in your
hand. Give it to her.
你手里的申请表 给她
Take this to the testing
area, put your name at the top,
拿着去测试区 表格顶端写好名字
sign the bottom, answer the
questions, bring it back. Next!
在最底下签名 答完问题再拿回来 下一个
Excuse me, but I have some
concerns about these questions.
对不起 关于这些问题 我有些疑问
Look at that sign up there.
看看那里的告示
Yes?
嗯?
Does it say "I give a damn"?
有没有写"我乐意搭理"呢?
No.
没有
That's because I don't.
那是因为我不乐意呗
Just look. See, this first
question makes no sense.
看一下啦 第一个问题讲不通啊
"How many car lengths should you
leave in front of you when driving?"
"开车时 你需距前车多少车长"
There's no possible way to answer that.
不可能有答案
A "car length" is not a
standardized unit of measure.
"车长"根本不是标准度量单位
Look at the sign.
看告示
Sheldon, it's "C." Just put down "C."
Sheldon 是C啦 选C就好了
I don't need your help, Penny.
Penny 我不要你帮忙
Listen to that little
girl, honey. Put "C." Next!
亲爱的 听那小姑娘的 选C 下一个
No, wait! No, hang on.
Look at this next question.
不 等下! 等等 看下一个问题
Sheldon, why are you
arguing with the DMV?
Sheldon 你干嘛要和车管局的争论呢?
How else are they going to learn?
我不吵他们咋学习进步啊?
Look... question two: When
are roadways most slippery?
看... 问题二: 什么时候路道最滑?
Now, okay, there are three
answers, none of which are correct.
瞧 三个答案 全是错的
The correct answer is "when covered by "a film of liquid
sufficient to reduce the coefficient of static friction"
正解是 当覆盖一层
足够减少摩擦系数的液体
"between the tire and the
road to essentially zero,
在轮胎和路之间达到零始态
but not so deep as to introduce
a new source of friction."
而这液态膜又不至于成为新的摩擦源
Here's your learner's permit. Go away.
你的驾驶学习许可 快走
But I'm not done. I have many additional
concerns about these questions.
还没说完呢 关于这些问题我还有很多疑问
Don't make me climb over this counter.
别逼我爬出柜台扁你
Come on. Let's go.
行了 走吧
Next!
下一个!
Aced it.
搞定
Okay, that's it. Let's boot it up.
好 成了 启动吧
Booting.
启动
This is a
state-of-the-art simulator.
这是最先进的模拟器
I adapted it from something a
friend of mine designed for the army.
我照一朋友给军方设计改装的
Is that why I appear to be in downtown Fallujah
behind the wheel of an up-armored Humvee?
所以我在费卢杰市区
跟在一辆全副武装的悍马后面?
I haven't configured it yet.
还没有完全改成民用程序
Let's see... Bradley tank...
transport truck... Batmobile...
我看看 布莱德利坦克
运输卡车  蝙蝠侠车
No.
别
Here we go. Red 2006 Ford Taurus
on the streets of Pasadena.
好了 帕萨迪纳市街道
2006款红色福特金牛星
What?
想说啥?
Statistically, red cars are stopped by
police far more often than any other color.
统计显示 红车远比其他车被警察扣的多
I don't want any hassles with the fuzz.
我可不想和警察争论
Fine, what color do you want?
行了 你想要啥色的?
You know the pale blue of
Luke Skywalker's lightsaber?
知道天行者路克光剑的灰蓝色不?
Before it was digitally remastered?
数码制作之前的那种?
Black, it is.
黑色 选定
Okay, now, what you want to do first is
turn on the ignition and shift into drive.
好了 首先你要点火然后挂挡
I haven't fastened my seat belt yet.
我还没有系上安全带呢
Okay, fasten your seat belt.
好啦 系上吧
****
系好了
Now, are there air bags?
有安全气囊吗?
You don't need air bags.
用不着的
What if a simulated van rear-ends me?
万一模拟货车追尾了呢?
I'll hit you in the face with a pillow.
我会用枕头打你脸的
Okay, now shift into drive.
好 现在换到驾驶档
Pull out slowly into traffic.
慢慢驶上路
Watch out, watch, watch
out for the pedestrians!
小心 小心路人!
Oh, God. Wait-- slow--
Hit the brakes! The brakes!
天 等等 慢点 刹车!刹车!
Thank you.
谢了
Sorry. Excuse me.
对不起 抱歉
My bad.
我的错
Student driver.
新手上路
How did you manage to get on the
second floor of the Glendale Galleria?
你怎么上的格兰岱尔商场二楼的?
I don't know. I was on
the Pasadena freeway.
不知道 我本来在帕萨迪纳高速路
I missed my exit, flew off the
overpass, and one thing led to another.
我错过出口 飞过天桥 接二连三的...
Maybe you want to give it a
rest and try again tomorrow.
也许你可以休息下 明天再练
No. I quit.
不 老子不干了
Aw, the pet store.
呀 宠物店
Remind me to compliment Wolowitz on
the software. It's amazingly detailed.
提醒我称赞Wolowitz的软件
细节太逼真了
So wait, you're just gonna give up?
那 你准备放弃了?
No, I'm not giving up. I never give up.
不 我才不放弃 我从不放弃
So, what is it you're doing?
那你这是干啥呢?
I'm... transcending the situation.
我正在... 度过难关呐
I'm clearly too evolved for driving.
显然驾驶对我来说太低级了
What does that mean?
啥意思呢?
Leonard, have you ever wondered why
my little toes and lateral incisors
Leonard 你纳闷过为啥
我的小脚趾和侧门牙
are significantly smaller than
the average for someone of my size?
要比和我一号的人小很多吗?
I wonder a lot of things about
you, Sheldon. But not-not that.
你有太多值得纳闷的 Sheldon
但这事没有过
Well, those are indicators that I'm farther along
the evolutionary scale than the average human.
那显示我比普通人进化得多
- No kidding.
- Well, no, no.
- 别搞笑了
- 别 听我说
I'm not gonna go so far as to say that I
represent a distinct new stage in humankind--
我也不好说我处于
人类发展的一个崭新阶段
you know, a homo novus, if you will.
你要是愿意的话 叫新新人类
No, that's for
anthropologists to decide.
不 那要人类学家来认定的
But I am convinced that the reason I
cannot master the plebeian task of driving
但是我确信我不能精通
普通人驾驶技术的原因
is because I'm not meant to.
是因为我注定不是干这个的
Yes, you are. You're meant
to learn how to drive.
不 你就是 你就是该学习驾驶的
- Please learn how to drive!
- No, no.
- 求你学学开车吧!
- 不 不
Leonard, I'm meant for greater things, like
unraveling the mysteries of the universe,
Leonard 我注定要做更伟大的事
比如解答宇宙的奥秘
not determining when it's safe to pass
a stopped school bus on a country road.
而不是搞清楚什么时候超过
一个停在乡村路上的校车是安全的
- It's never safe.
- Yeah, well, I know that now.
- 啥时候都不安全
- 好极了 我现在知道了
Fine. Assuming that
everything you say is true,
好 假定你说的都是真的
how does the biologically superior
homo novus get to work tomorrow morning?
我们生物角度极其优越的新新人类
明天怎么去上班呢?
Homo novus doesn't know.
新新人类不知道
Well, hang in there.
那 耐心等吧
Maybe you'll evolve into
something with wings.
也许你会进化出翅膀的
Good morning, gentlemen.
早上好 先生们
Good morning.
早上好
Is there some new kind of
casual Friday I don't know about?
还有我不知道的星期五便装日?
No, he lives here now.
不是 他住在这里了
Really? Why?
是不是哟? 为啥?
Well, since he won't take the
bus and he's too evolved to drive,
既然他不能做公车
又进化过了人类驾驶的阶段
he decided it would be easier
to just sleep in his office
他觉得等到我完成我的实验前
and shower in the radiation lab
until I'm finished with my experiment.
办公室睡觉和在辐射实验室
洗澡会好熬些
But you finished your
experiment a week ago.
但你一周前就完成了
Yep.
对
********
天啦
又出现了
********
肯定是老鼠
老鼠不会烤面包
********
更不会剥面包皮
You saw nothing!
当作啥也没看见!
本论坛字幕仅翻译交流学习之用
禁止任何商业用途否则后果自负